陳家昌議員。
多謝，主席。
本會現在恢復。
CTCs， in abbreviation。
修訂誒，修訂條例草案。
RSCs， in abbreviation.
Make provisions for profits tax purposes.
我會報道主要的議事委員會的決議。
and treat regulatory capital securities as debt securities.
法案委員會已舉行三場會議，與行政局討論法案。
二零一五年税務修訂第四號條例草案二讀辯論。
regarding interests on money borrowed from, or lent to associated corporations.
審議條例草案嘅委員會主席梁繼昌議員就委員會嘅報告向本會發言。
In my capacity as chairman of the Bills Committee on Inland Revenue, Amendment Number Four Bill 2015.
The bill seeks to amend the Inland Revenue Ordinance to give profits tax concession to qualifying corporate treasury centres.
The bill would also amend the stamp duties ordinance to give stamp duty relief in relation to regulatory capital securities.
通過《The Banking Ordinance》。
和銀行 capita rules。
under the inland revenue ordinance.
是目前不税 deductible。
The Basel III capital adequacy requirements.
and their distributions are not deductible for profits tax purposes.
expressed as a percentage of their total risk-weighted assets.
A CTC is an in-house bank within a multinational corporation.
and to reduce the profits tax for specified treasury activities by 50%.
The Basel III requirements have been gradually implemented in Hong Kong since 2013.
但利息收入 arise from its intra-group financing business is chargeable to profits tax.
利息開支由C.T.C. operating in Hong Kong， payable to an overseas associated corporation。
這些Tier Two或Tier Two instrument、Tier One或Tier Two instrument，是，然而，不被視為是dead instruments。
The bill seeks to change these rules and to allow such interest deductions under specified conditions for CTCs.
是最低標準，under which financial institutions must hold certain amount of regulatory capital.
金融機構可能尋求遵守巴薩爾三要求，通過強化其資本基於，其中其他方式，發行額外Tier One或Tier Two工具，以籌集資金。
may qualify as a CTC.
under Hong Kong's current tax regime.
may benefit from the proposed tax measures.
如果它不接收股息從其集團公司。
Members have queried if an investment holding company.
for both deduction and taxation purposes, under the ordinance.
the bills committee supports the bill and the objectives it seeks to achieve.
which also carries out corporate treasury activities for other group companies.
and adding new provisions to treat a R C R C S as debt security.
The policy objective of maintaining a simple tax regime in Hong Kong remains unchanged.
The administration advises that a holding company which is also performing some CTC functions.
The administration explains that the proposals are introduced in line with evolving international development and standards.
所以，那 distributions arise from the security， other than the repayment of the paid-up amount， should be treated as interest。
Members have expressed concerns whether Hong Kong would gradually deviate from its simple tax regime by offering tax concessions from time to time.
The bill seeks to amend the inland revenue ordinance by defining regulatory capital security to cover an 81T2 instruments, that is essentially a debt in nature.
另一方面， sums received by a person as distributions of RCS or profits from the disposal or on the redemption of RCS are chargeable to profits tax under certain circumstances.
在提供信貸時。
The source of interest income.
在case of the operation test。
在其他部分的內地税收條例。
在 Assessing profits, tax or deductions.
The difference between the two tests is that.
The provision of credit test is normally used.
Whether or not the holding company receives dividends.
在確定的收入來源的CTC。
委員會指出，該法案採用操作測試。
to be subject to the concessionary tax in respect of its qualifying profits.
provided that it satisfies the criteria for being a qualifying CTC under the bill.
One looks to see what the taxpayer has done to earn the profit in question, and where he has done it.
and seventy five percent or more of the assets used to carry out corporate treasury activities.
從其集團公司，是 not relevant， as dividend income is not subject to tax in Hong Kong.
A safe harbour is introduced, which allows corporations having 75% or more of their profits derived from.
and a chargeable to profits tax.
follows the current practice in the Indian Revenue Department.
And would forestall aggressive tax-avoiding schemes.
for deeming interest income to CTCs as trading receipts.
The application of the operation test on interest income.
One member queries whether the use of the operation test.
It is necessary to include asymmetric tax treatment.
The bill dims interest income received by a CTC to be trading receipts.
and relevant gains or profits arise from an intra-group financing business.
this would avoid giving the impression that Hong Kong is becoming a tax haven.
The proposed provision of the bill would codify this practice and the legal principles involved.
是the place where the funds from which the interest income is derived were provided to the borrower.
arise in or derived from Hong Kong from a trade, profession or business carried on in Hong Kong.
The administration has assured the bills committee that no new taxation principle is introduced in the bill.
The administration explains that, as new tax deduction provisions are introduced for interest expenses by CTCs.
and the deeming provision would defeat the objective of promoting Hong Kong as a place for international corporations to set up CTCs.
In respect of that interest.
After the passage of the bill.
and practice notes to be issued.
行政會同意。
Some members query whether the requirements of subject to tax.
一公司，which has to pay tax in respect of an interest.
refers to tax that has been paid or will be paid.
And no change is to be made to existing taxation principles.
After setting off its loss against the profits, will be considered as having been subject to tax.
The company incurs a substantial loss for a long period, and has not paid any tax.
The subject to tax condition would not be regarded as having been satisfied if, for example.
和 whether interest deduction would be allowed if the lender is in a loss situation.
The bill proposes that a CTC in Hong Kong may deduct interest expenses on money borrowed from a non-Hong Kong associated corporation.
provided that the amount of interest received by the non-Hong Kong associated corporation is subject to a similar tax in a territory outside Hong Kong.
The Inland Revenue Department would elaborate the application of the subject to tax condition in departmental departmental interpretation.
行政解釋，那，個概念的替代税，包括案例，當税已經繳納，和税將會繳納。
The bill deals with profits and deductions.
of the tax deduction provisions of the bill.
and the amount of deduction allowable costs and expenses.
In respect of a transaction between a company and a financial institution.
是 not to exceed the amount that would have been incurred by the Hong Kong branch on this basis.
by allocating a large proportion of the RCS to its branch office in Hong Kong.
一些成員有表達過擔憂，是否包括這條特別的企業條款？
arise from the issuance of RCS through a Hong Kong branch of a multinational corporation.
profits will be attributed as if the Hong Kong branch and other parts of the financial institution were separate enterprises.
might put Hong Kong at an disadvantage, as similar restrictions are absent in other tax regimes.
arise from the transaction in RCS between the Hong Kong branch and its parent company, parent institution.
臂長指的係條件，兩方交易的參與方沒有任何關係。
在certifying the chargeable profits of the Hong Kong branch of an overseas financial institution, whose capital is raised through the issuance of RCs,
The administration advises that the proposed provision was introduced as a safeguard against potential abuse by non-resident financial institutions.
The administration advises that a more stringent test is to be applied, in order to align with the latest international practices for prevention of tax avoidance.
成員們也查詢過，為什麼該法案在決定是否允許在CPC上扣除利息支出時，比在其他情況下更為嚴格？
for the avoidance of doubt.
It would not be beneficial to Hong Kong.
with both the features of debt and equity.
The administration subsequently advises that.
Taking into account the concerns expressed by the sector.
The bill includes a section 17H to specify.
因為LCS係高利率混合工具。
行政 advises that such provision is necessary.
行政解釋，那，the arms-length principle enables the inland revenue department.
and suggest that the administration reconsider the need for such provision.
and the advice from the Bills Committee over the interpretation of the proposed Section 17H.
一些成員已反映該業界對此條款可能影響非銀行公司的運作表示擔憂。
If a non-resident financial institution could enjoy huge tax deduction by allocating excessive RCS to its local Hong Kong branch office,
To determine accurately and objectively the profit that a branch office of a non-resident financial institution generates in Hong Kong from the transactions in RCS.
Some members have queried whether it is appropriate to apply the arm's length principle to handle the relationship between a non-resident financial institution and its local branch office in Hong Kong.
that the provisions applying the arm's length principle and separate enterprise principle in connection with transaction in RCS will not affect the operation of other provisions under the inland revenue ordinance that apply the same principles.
And next.
在這 respect。
That is 8.25%。
要 allow a corporate borrower.
第二係要 mandate I O。
先生，主席，這條法案有兩個主要目的。
for qualifying CTCs with qualifying profits.
要移除，的提出第17H。
行政會將提出委員會階段的修訂。
and all references to the section from the bill.
I would like to give my personal views on this bill.
carry on in Hong Kong as an intra-group financing business.
Two important changes to the treatment of interest has been introduced.
One is to introduce a concessionary profit tax rate that is half of the standard tax rate.
委員會notes， The resumption of the second reading debate on the bill at today's council meeting.
第一目的係實施一個共同財政中心税制，為提供一個 conducive 環境，給多國企業到亞洲設立全球及區域 CTS、CTCs。
Under specified conditions.
deduction of interest.
那利息收入。
在jurisdiction outside Hong Kong.
which will require, amongst others.
The administration has also taken this opportunity.
as opposed to the provision of credit tests.
arising from the same loan transaction is subject to tax.
under this special set of circumstances.
to clarify the application of the operation test.
但 careful analysis of case laws and practice.
In order to minimise any chance of aggressive tax avoidance practice.
payable on money borrowed from a non-Hong Kong associated corporation.
Mr. President, this indeed has created some controversies during the committee stage of the bill.
for the ascertainment of interest income subject to profits tax under the CTC regime.
have drawn most parties, including myself, to the observation that this is indeed the right approach to ascertain the taxability of interest income.
Next.
In fact.
under the RCS regime.
第二個目的係。
被 treated as debt instruments.
我會嘗試 Highlight 一 few Lessons。
Well, after the passage of this bill.
一 major tax uncertainty for banks.
which possess hybrid features of debts and equity.
which issue additional tier one and additional tier two instruments.
金融機構，無論有總部喺香港或 not。
which I repeatedly point out to the government in the past two years.
是 to clarify the tax treatment of regulated capital securities (RCS).
我因此相當 happy，that the government has taken my suggestion and implemented legislation to clarify the tax position.
Distribution from these instruments will be treated as interest for interest deduction and assessment of profits tax purpose.
我有，and I would like to share this with my fellow colleagues. Being the chairman of this bills committee and other revenue-related bills committee.
second.
Mr. President, next.
my third observation.
to narrow down any differences.
Revenue bills are always very technical.
although there were only three committee meetings for this bill.
任何 ambigu ambiguity must be avoided.
和部門的解讀和實踐註釋。
In order to expedite the legislative process.
I would like to look at the macro policy implications of this bill.
和法律，我 believe 必須被草擬成平實語言。
before attending the meeting and facing questions before the members of the Bills Committee.
我會勸兩者，即係部門，要有個清晰的主意喺度。
There have been indeed far more behind-the-scenes meetings and discussions in order to expedite the passage of the bill.
我認為，必須有明確的分界線，將要處理的內容，與主要立法。
The chairman of any bills committee must have a keen interest in the subject matter, and be able to actively engage all relevant parties.
我 believe。
我會想引用幾個數字。
香港會，我 hope。
Indeed，upon reflection。
on 25 March for corporate treasury activities.
regain its rightful position in this index next year.
作為鄰居，正漸漸追上，甚至可能超越我們。
Our tax environment may not be as competitive as five or ten years ago.
This is in direct response to the impending passage of this bill.
yet Hong Kong still has clear advantages in certain other areas.
香港，作為一個企業財務中心，仍然非常吸引。
一啲的macro policy reasons for introducing the bill is to improve Hong Kong's role and competitiveness as a prime financial centre.
however，香港should not become complacent nor dismissive about what we have achieved，or what we are going to achieve as a major financial centre.
新加坡最近將其營業税率，對CTC活動，從10%降至8%。
Although Hong Kong has slipped from the third position to fourth position as a global financial centre in accordance with the Global Financial Index published by the Exact Yang Group.
An objective analysis will support that, after the passage of this bill, Hong Kong will still be as attractive as Singapore as a location for CTC.
作為領先金融中心。
800億美元在新加坡。
amount of assets owned by the banking sector.
versus 14 billion US dollars in Singapore.
在新加坡，需要預 approval 和清關程序。
先生，我會考慮以下兩項税收政策，需要考慮為優先事項。
Indeed, looking into the future, there indeed are the tax measures which the government should make.
數目上，foreign banks in Hong Kong have 145 versus 117 in Singapore.
In order to enhance our position as a primary financial centre, while protecting our revenue base.
在香港，的公司就 simply 需要編譯和提交正常的年度税報。
作為一月二零一五，喺香港，我哋有二點四兆美元，versus。
The first of these is the due consideration of tax regime for the leasing industry, especially the aircraft leasing industry.
amount of corporate bonds issue and that was a two hundred and one four figure, thirty three billion US dollars in Hong Kong.
and indeed, simplified procedures in obtaining tax concession under the tax regime has put Hong Kong at an advantage.
Now, first of all, we note that Hong Kong does have, as a financial centre, has certain international obligations to fulfil, whether they are evoked by the OECD, G20 or other supranational organisation.
But we need to conserve our resources and energy to make things work for Hong Kong, and to push out other tax policies favourable to the sustainable development of Hong Kong.
我會勸。
There are two directions.
財經事務及庫務局局長。
有冇其他議員要發言？
第二方向，Mr. President。
and also, corporations to issue green bond in Hong Kong.
But I also note that any policy conducive to air leasing, aircraft leasing.
主席，我已 conclude 我的報告，並已做過我需要的 Remarks。
may also be applicable to ship leasing, as the tax principles are basically the same for the two industries.
The parties and my colleagues across the spectrum in this chamber to give support to this bill. Thank you.
税 incentives can be considered to encourage private equity business investing into green business.
And second, will be to extend the depreciation allowance to the user of leased aircraft or ships.
for a tax regime conducive to the leasing industry, one is to offer a special tax rate for the industry.
政策-wise，我會belief， it is difficult to explain why the government should favour one industry to another in offering a concessionary tax rate.
And for that reason, as a gut reaction, I personally would prefer a revamp of the depreciation allowance regime on plants and machinery used by business.
The recent release of the report on Hong Kong as a regional green finance hub by the Financial Services Development Council a few days ago is indeed an encouraging effort and achievement.
即係百分之八點二五。
嚟到條例草案嘅審議工作順利完成。
將定為現行企業利得税率嘅一半。
政府研究委員會提出嘅意見之後，收議。
為使利息收入嘅税務處理達至對稱。
我都感謝不同團體向法案委員會表達意見。
誒法案委員會今日舉行咗三次會議，討論條例草案嘅內容。
同時，佢同時條例草案調整現行嘅利息扣除規則。
容許在香港經營集團內部融資業務嘅企業借款人。
條例草案旨在提升香港吸引企業財資中心落户嘅優勢。
建議修正若干條文，我會稍後喺喺喺稍後嘅全體委員會審議階段動議有關嘅修正案。
為此，條例草案定明適用於合資格企業財資中心嘅利得税寬減税率。
亦可以按半額税率課税，我相信呢個有助吸引更多企業在香港經營財資業務。
誒主席，我感謝二零一五年税務修訂第四號條例草案法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員同埋各位委員所付出嘅努力。
條例草案亦訂立咗安全港規則，使使利用使利潤主要來自經營企業財資活動，而資產亦主要用於該等活動嘅企業。
在符合指明條件嘅情況下，從應平税利潤應平税利潤中扣除向非香港商聯法團借款所需支付嘅利息。
視為利息開支。
非香港商聯法團。
為壓制税基。
並支持條例草案所載列嘅建議。
使就該等證券支付嘅款項。
政府在草擬條文時，以確保建議語。
償還該證券嘅已付數額除外。
侵蝕和利潤轉移而設嘅最新國際標準相符。
資本充足要求所發行監管資本債券嘅税務處理。
可於計算銀行嘅應平税利潤時，從利潤從利潤中扣除。
此外，條例草案再有條文，以釐清銀行為遵守巴塞爾協定三。
同時，現行市債券嘅分派或利潤款項為應課利得税。
法案委員會曾討論有關措施嘅涵蓋範圍、相關條件以及防止避税條款等。
有關嘅修訂，旨在把銀行發行嘅監管資本證券視為債務證券。
條例草案定明，如某集團在香港經營集團內部融資業務中，貸款與
則即使貸款是在香港境外提供，有關利息收入仍會被當作是源自香港的利息收入，需繳納利得税。
將如其他。
遵從適用嘅。
反對嘅請舉手。
條例草案亦便利銀行。
銀行業界對上述建議表示支持。
相應地，監管資本證券嘅轉讓。
條例草案亦定定咗適當嘅防止避税條文。
推動香港總部經濟及商業樞紐嘅發展。
債券相關嘅轉讓交易一樣，會獲印花税寬免。
我認為議題獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
為咗執行條例草案所在的各項税務措施，税務局會在條例。
勘憲生效後，發出適宜及執行指引，詳細解釋技術細節及執行安排。
現在各位提出嘅代決議題係二零一五年税務修訂第四號條例草案，予以議讀。咁現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
嘅營業收入嘅規定，亦會適用於監管資本證券嘅分派或利潤款項。
國際監管資本要求，我懇請議員支持條例草案及各項稍後提出嘅修正案。主席，我僅此陳詞。
主席，條例草案對吸引更多企業在香港成立財資中心尤為重要，有助帶動對本地金融及專業服務行業嘅需求。
全體委員會審議階段，本。
二零一五年税務修訂第四號條例草案。